Richard M. Nixon Reference Collection, 1934-1999
Duke University. University Archives
Richard M. Nixon Reference collection 1934-1999
Duke University. University Archives
0.5 linear feet Extent: 500 Items
Richard Milhous Nixon (1913-1994) attended the Duke University School of Law from 1934 to 1937, graduating number three in a class of twenty-six. During his three years at Duke, Nixon was active in the Duke Bar Association and was elected President in his senior year. The Richard M. Nixon Reference Collection contains academic transcripts, personal and administrative correspondence related to law school, letters of recommendation, newspaper clippings, and reference inquiries and correspondence related to both the honorary degree controversy in 1954 and the Watergate scandal in the early 1970's when he was President of the United States. This collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research.
UA.01.11.0036
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Provenance
The Richard M. Nixon Reference Collection was compiled from various sources by University Archives staff for reference and research.
Subject Headings
Duke University. School of Law; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994 -- Correspondence; Presidents -- United States -- History -- 20th century
Related Material
Inventory of the Nixon Library Controversy collection 1981-2001
University Archives, Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Container List1934-1999, 1 Box
  - School of Law, 1934 (Box 1)
  - School of Law, 1935-1937 May (Box 1)
  - School of Law - Term Paper, 1936 (Box 1)
  - School of Law, 1937 Jul-1938 (Box 1)
  - School of Law, 1940-1963 (Box 1)
  - School of Law, 1965-1973 Oct (Box 1)
  - School of Law, 1973 Nov-1975 (Box 1)
  - School of Law - Bumper Stickers, 1974 (Box 1)
  - School of Law - Transcripts, Grades & Professor, 1934-1937 (Box 1)
  - Duke Bar Association - President [R.M. Nixon Correspondence], 1936 (Box 1)
  - Duke Bar Association - President [R.M. Nixon Correspondence], 1937 (Box 1)
  - Duke Bar Association - Ephemera from Nixon Years, 1935-1937 (Box 1)
  - Duke News Service - Correspondence, 1952, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Duke University - President A.H. Edens, 1952-1960 (Box 1)
  - Duke University - President A.H. Edens [Richard M. Nixon Honorary Degree Controversy], 1954 Mar-July (Box 1)
  - Duke University - President D.M. Knight, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Duke University - President Terry Sanford, 1970-1974 (Box 1)
  - Robert F. Durden Papers [Richard Nixon], 1987 (Box 1)
  - Calvin B. Hoover Papers [Richard Nixon Correspondence], 1954-1967 (Box 1)
  - Bridget Booker Correspondence, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, Miscellaneous, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Newspapers - Kansas City Star: 'Life Story of Nixon', 1955 October 30-November 6 (Box 1)
  - Gosnell, Jack (Box 1)